Elom Tettey KWAMIN, FRM

PERSONAL DATA

Address: Projensdorfer Strasse 10, 24106 Kiel, Germany

PHONE: +49 17645950661 EMAIL: et.kwamin@gmail.com

Summary

Detail-oriented and experienced Analyst with a strong interest in the capital markets and a good knowledge of financial markets and products. Working experience in pricing and validating model prices of Bonds and other OTC instruments as well as experience in assessing credit risk inherent in structured finance transactions. Good programming knowledge in Python and VBA. Possess strong statistical and analytical skills.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Jun 2021-Present

Specialist - Structured Finance Analyst at Scope Ratings GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Perform annual review of rated deals to reassess their current ratings as lead analyst on a number of NPL ABS and Consumer ABS transactions
- Automate parts of the analytical steps improving overall efficiency of the monitoring process
- \bullet Contribute to the development of Scope's structured finance rating methodologies

 $\mathrm{Dec}\ 2020\text{-May}\ 2021$

Associate Analyst - Structured Finance Analyst at Scope Ratings GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Provide support to the lead rating analysts on assessing structured finance transactions; asset analysis, counterparty analysis and structural credit analysis as well as cash flow modelling and documentation review
- Perform data analysis on transaction data tapes received for new rating assignments and monitoring reviews
- \bullet Contribute to the development of Scope's structured finance rating methodologies
- Take part in analytical operational review visits and maintain a close relationship with market participants in the market meetings with issuers and arrangers

Dec 2019-Nov 2020

Trainee - Structured Finance Analyst at Scope Ratings GmbH, Berlin, Germany

- Analyze a broad span of structured finance asset classes with a primary focus on securitization transactions including Consumer and SME ABS, RMBS and NPL ABS
- Provide support to the lead rating analysts on assessing structured finance transactions; asset analysis, counterparty analysis and structural credit analysis as well as cash flow modelling and documentation review
- \bullet Analyze and monitor market developments in European structured finance and publish timely topical market research

Oct 2018-Apr 2019

Junior Quantitative Analyst at SMARTTRA.DE, Berlin, Germany

- \bullet Ensuring high quality through software testing of new developments and utilizing automated regression test frameworks.
- Assisting support line in specific analytic related client requests.
- Writing specifications and documentations for new and improved processes.
- Generating and validating model prices of Bonds and other OTC products.
- ullet Making coverage checks for structured products and set them up for production and delivery to clients.
- Writing and implementing classes and methods in the Java financial library.
- Refactoring existing code in the Java financial library to optimize performance.

$Mar\ 2018\text{-Sep}\ 2018$

Intern as Junior Quantitative Analyst at SMARTTRA.DE, Berlin, Germany

- Generating and Validating model prices for clients
- Automating some daily processes using Java programming software
- \bullet Improving the pricing library by refactoring classes to make codes more efficient
- Setting up new product requests from clients for production
- Updating the database daily with current market data used for different production purposes.
- Running different daily automated processes in Java and Python.

Sep 2012-Aug 2013

Teaching Assistant at KWAME NKRUMAH UNIVERSITY OF SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY, Kumasi, Ghana

- \bullet Organizing regression analysis and statistics tutorials for undergraduate students
- Grading mid-semester examination for undergraduate students

EDUCATION

Sep 2015-Jul 2017	Master of Science in QUANTITATIVE ECONOMICS Christian-Albrechts Universität zu Kiel, Kiel, GERMANY
Sep 2013-Oct 2016	Master of Science in QUANTITATIVE FINANCE Christian-Albrechts Universität zu Kiel, Kiel, GERMANY
Aug 2008-Jun 2012	Bachelor of Science in Actuarial Science (First Class Honours) Kwame Nkrumah University of Science and Technology, Kumasi, GHANA
Sep 2004-Jun 2007	Senior High School Certificate St. Peter's Senior High, Nkwatia-Kwahu, Ghana

Professional Qualifications

Jul 2018 - Nov 2019 Financial Risk Manager (FRM)

Global Association of Risk Professionals (GARP)

Aug 2018 - Present Chartered Financial Analyst (CFA) Passed Level I
Chartered Financial Analyst Institute (CFA Institute)

LANGUAGES

English: Bilingual Proficiency

German: Intermediate Knowledge (B1)

Computer Skills

Basic Knowledge: SQL

Good Knowledge: Microsoft Office Suite(Word, Powerpoint, Excel), VBA, Python

Interests and Activities

Creating tools for task automation, Programming, Machine Learning

Portfolio Management, Risk Management

Football, Volleyball, Travelling